## SHEA KEOGH

shealmk@gmail.com | 0838411548 | Dublin, Ireland https://sheakeogh.github.io

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced Software Engineer with a passion for engineering and development. I am a hard worker who enjoys problem-solving and working both individually and as a part of a team.

Skilled in a myriad of different technologies for web applications and application development. Experience working with Cloud Platforms - Pivotal Cloud Foundry(PCF) and Amazon Web Services(AWS), Maven, Spring Boot, and REST/SOAP API.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Software Developer Consultant, Decision Inc. Australia Feb 2024 - Sep 2024

- Led the design and implementation of an ETL solution to support Australian State Governments with their financial processes.
- Provided troubleshooting and technical support, collaborating with clients to maintain full functionality of the solution.
- Enhanced existing software engineering standards and introduced new best practices within the development team to improve code quality and efficiency.

#### Software Engineer, Mastercard

Sep 2022 - Sep 2023

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design, develop, and maintain complex software systems, ensuring scalability and performance.
- Implemented new features and enhancements, leading to an increase in product functionality and improved user experience.
- Introduced automation testing and a new way of performance testing to Mastercard's APIs for improved monitoring.
- Conducted code reviews, identified and resolved bugs, and optimized codebase for efficiency

#### Web Developer, Freelance

Jan 2022 - Sep 2023

- Independently managed client projects, ranging from small businesses to startups, to develop custom web applications and websites.
- Translated client requirements into technical specifications, designed responsive user interfaces, and integrated interactive features.
- Provided ongoing maintenance and support, ensuring the longevity and performance of delivered projects.
- Developed e-commerce platforms, blogs, and portfolio websites, enhancing clients' online presence.

#### **EDUCATION**

### Bachelor of Engineering

Sep 2018 - May 2022

**Dublin City University** 

- Electronic and Computer Engineering Major in Internet of Things.
- Final Grade: 2.1

#### **KEY SKILLS**

#### **Technical Skills**

- Object-Oriented Programming
- Backend Development
- Java Spring Framework
- Python Development
- DevOps
- CI/CD

#### **Personal Skills**

- Effective Communication
- Collaboration
- Adaptability
- · Problem Solving